Sculpture Photograph Collection: Austria-Israel
Yale University Arts Library
- France (Box 93)
  - Known Artists., 1381 (Box 107)
    - S, 65 (Box 129)
      - Individual Artists., 56 (Box 129)
        - Sluter, Claus, and School of, XV C., 53 (Box 129)
          - Tomb of Jean Sans Peur and Marguerite de Baviere., 14 (Box 129)
          - Tombs of Philippe the Bold and Jean Sans Peur., 9 (Box 129)
          - Well of Moses., 12 (Box 129)
    - T, 12 (Box 130)
      - Miscellaneous Artists., 2 (Box 130)
        - Takis, 1925-., 1 (Box 130)
        - Turcan, Jean, 1846-1895., 1 (Box 130)
      - Individual Artists., 10 (Box 130)
        - Thury, Pierre de, active 1413-1435., 7 (Box 130)
        - Tuby, Jean-Baptiste, 1635-1700., 3 (Box 130)
    - U, V, W, X, Y, Z, 5 (Box 130)
      - Miscellaneous Artists., 5 (Box 130)
        - Varin, Jean, 1596-1672., 1 (Box 130)
        - Vasse, Louis Claude, 1716-1772., 1 (Box 130)
        - Veyrier, Christophe, 1637-1689., 2 (Box 130)
        - Waroquier, Henry de, 1881-., 1 (Box 130)
- Germany (Box 131)
  - Anonymous Artists., 498 (Box 131)
    - Works from before XI Century and miscellany., 18 (Box 131)
    - XI Century., 92 (Box 131)
      - Miscellaneous locations., 24 (Box 131)
      - Augsburg., 6 (Box 131)
      - Hildesheim., 62 (Box 132)
        - Miscellaneous works., 1 (Box 132)
        - Bronze doors., 54 (Box 132)
          - Overviews., 7 (Box 132)
          - Left door., 21 (Box 132)
          - Right door., 26 (Box 132)
        - Bronze Easter column., 7 (Box 132)
    - XII Century., 24 (Box 132)
      - Miscellaneous works., 23 (Box 132)
      - Bronze doors., 1 (Box 132)
    - XIII Century., 63 (Box 133)
      - Miscellaneous locations., 40 (Box 133)
      - Hildesheim., 8 (Box 133)
      - Magdeburg., 6 (Box 133)
      - Naumburg., 9 (Box 133)
    - XIV Century., 58 (Box 134)
      - Miscellaneous locations., 27 (Box 134)
      - Berlin., 5 (Box 134)
      - Cologne., 8 (Box 134)
      - Erfurt., 3 (Box 134)
      - Frankfurt., 2 (Box 134)
      - Halberstadt., 4 (Box 134)
      - Lubeck., 4 (Box 134)
      - Vienna., 5 (Box 134)
    - XV Century., 109 (Box 135)
      - Miscellaneous works., 94 (Box 135, Box 136)
      - Danubian School., 2 (Box 136)
      - Master of Kefermarkt., 13 (Box 136)
    - XVI Century., 103 (Box 137)
      - General works., 71 (Box 137)
        - Miscellaneous works., 3 (Box 137)
        - Figures., 25 (Box 137)
        - Groups., 25 (Box 137)
          - Miscellaneous works., 16 (Box 137)
          - Tomb of Maximilian, 1502-1580., 9 (Box 137)
        - Reliefs., 18 (Box 138)
      - Danubian School., 9 (Box 138)
      - Master H L, active c.1510-1533., 9 (Box 138)
      - Master of Maurer., 14 (Box 138)
    - XVII Century., 9 (Box 138)
    - XVIII Century., 14 (Box 138)
    - XIX to XX Century., 8 (Box 138)
  - Known Artists., 774 (Box 139)
    - A, 18 (Box 139)
      - Miscellaneous Artists., 5 (Box 139)
        Includes a folder containing a catalogue from a Hans Aeschbacher show.
        - Apengeter, Hans, XIV C., 3 (Box 139)
        - Arp, Sophie Tauber, 1889-1943., 1 (Box 139)
        - Auvera, Jakob van der, 1672-1760., 1 (Box 139)
      - Individual Artists., 13 (Box 139)
        - Asam, Egid Quirin, 1692-1750., 13 (Box 139)
    - B, 66 (Box 139)
      - Miscellaneous Artists., 10 (Box 139)
        - Barwig, Franz, 1868-., 1 (Box 139)
        - Baselitz, Georg, 1938-., 2 (Box 139)
        - Baur, Johann Leonhard, 1681-1760., 1 (Box 139)
        - Begas, Reinhold, 1831-1911., 1 (Box 139)
        - Berthold, Joachim, 1917-., 1 (Box 139)
        - Bohm, Johann Heinrich, active 1673., 1 (Box 139)
        - Breitenauer, I. A., 1757-1838., 1 (Box 139)
        - Bronisch, Paul, XX C., 1 (Box 139)
        - Bschorrer, J. G., 1692-1763., 1 (Box 139)
      - Individual Artists., 56 (Box 139)
        - Barlach, Ernst, 1870-1938., 17 (Box 139)
        - Belling, Rudolf, 1886-1972., 6 (Box 139)
        - Bellmer, Hans, 1902-1975., 6 (Box 139)
        - Berg, Claus, XVI C., 8 (Box 139)
        - Beuys, Joseph, 1921-1986., 10 (Box 140)
        - Breker, Arno, 1900-., 3 (Box 140)
        - Brueggemann, Hans, 1480-1540., 6 (Box 140)
    - C, 1 (Box 140)
      - Miscellaneous Artists., 1 (Box 140)
        - Cauer, R., XIX C., 1 (Box 140)
    - D, 30 (Box 140)
      - Miscellaneous Artists., 6 (Box 140)
        - Daucher, Adolf, 1460-1523., 1 (Box 140)
        - Daucher, Hans, c.1486-1538., 1 (Box 140)
        - Douvermann, Heinrich, active 1510-1544., 1 (Box 140)
        - Dreyer, Benedict, c.1480- after 1555., 2 (Box 140)
        - Duren, Adam von, XV C., 1 (Box 140)
      - Individual Artists., 24 (Box 140)
        - Dannecker, Johann Heinrich von, 1758-1841., 4 (Box 140)
        - Dietrich, Joachim von, active 1736-1753., 6 (Box 140)
        - Dietz, Ferdinand, 1708-1777., 12 (Box 140)
        - Donner, George Raphael, 1693-1741., 2 (Box 140)
    - E, 30 (Box 140)
      - Miscellaneous Artists., 3 (Box 140)
        - Eberhard, Konrad, 1768-1859., 1 (Box 140)
        - Einbeck, Konrad von, XV C., 1 (Box 140)
        - Elhafen, Ignaz, 1658-1715., 1 (Box 140)
      - Individual Artists., 27 (Box 140)
        - Egell, Paul, 1691-1752., 5 (Box 140)
        - Erhart, Gregor, active 1460-1540, and Michael, active 1469-1518., 12 (Box 140)
        - Ernst, Max, 1891-1976., 10 (Box 140)
    - F, 20 (Box 141)
      - Miscellaneous Artists., 4 (Box 141)
        - Fehrenbach, Gerson, 1932-., 1 (Box 141)
        - Fiori, Ernesto de, 1884-1945., 2 (Box 141)
        - Franz, Carl J., 1829-1875., 1 (Box 141)
      - Individual Artists., 16 (Box 141)
        - Feichtmayer, Joseph Anton, 1696-1770., 16 (Box 141)
    - G, 46 (Box 141)
      - Miscellaneous Artists., 13 (Box 141)
        - Geldmacher, Klaus, 1940-., 1 (Box 141)
        - Gerhaert, Nicolaus, active 1463-1473., 3 (Box 141)
        - Goeritz, Mathias, 1915-., 1 (Box 141)
        - Gradler, XIX C., 1 (Box 141)
        - Gras, Caspar, 1590-1674., 1 (Box 141)
        - Grasser, Erasmus, 1450-1518., 2 (Box 141)
        - Groninger, F. W., XVIII C.?, 1 (Box 141)
        - Gropius, Walter, 1883-1969., 2 (Box 141)
        - Gudewerdt, Hans, c.1600-1671., 1 (Box 141)
      - Individual Artists., 33 (Box 141)
        - Gerhard, Hubert, c.1540/50-1620., 3 (Box 141)
        - Gunther, Ignaz, 1725-1775., 30 (Box 141)
    - H, 43 (Box 142)
      - Miscellaneous Artists., 13 (Box 142)
        - Hagnower, Nikolaus, c.1455-c.1526., 1 (Box 142)
        - Hahn, Hermann, 1868-1942., 2 (Box 142)
        - Hagenauer, Friederich, active 1520-1545., 1 (Box 142)
        - Haller, Hermann, 1880-1950., 1 (Box 142)
        - Hartung, Karl, 1908-., 1 (Box 142)
        - Heiliger, Bernhard, 1915-., 1 (Box 142)
        - Heimann, E., XX C., 1 (Box 142)
        - Hencke, Peter, -1777., 1 (Box 142)
        - Herlin, Friedrich, c.1435-1500., 1 (Box 142)
        - Herzog, Oswald, 1881-., 1 (Box 142)
        - Heyde, Henning von der, c.1487-c.1520., 1 (Box 142)
        - Hierle, A., active 1701-1753., 1 (Box 142)
      - Individual Artists., 30 (Box 142)
        - Haacke, Hans, 1936-., 1 (Box 142)
        - Hajek, Otto Herbert, 1927-., 8 (Box 142)
        - Hesse, Eva, 1936-1970., 7 (Box 142)
        - Heyde, Henning von der, c.1487-c.1520., 2 (Box 142)
        - Hildebrand, Adolf von, 1847-1921., 6 (Box 142)
        - Horn, Rebecca, 1944-., 6 (Box 142)
    - I, J, 3 (Box 142)
      - Miscellaneous Artists., 3 (Box 142)
        - Jaenisch, Hans, 1907-., 1 (Box 142)
        - Jorhan, Christian the Elder, 1727-1804., 2 (Box 142)
    - K, 68 (Box 143)
      - Miscellaneous Artists., 7 (Box 143)
        - Kampann, Rudiger-Utz, 1935-., 1 (Box 143)
        - Kern, Leonhard, and workshop of, 1588-1663., 2 (Box 143)
        - Kirchner, Heinrich, 1902-., 2 (Box 143)
        - Krausser, J. K., 1874-., 1 (Box 143)
          Date may be for the sculpture, not the artist s birth.
        - Kuhn, Dina, XX C., 1 (Box 143)
        - Kurschner, F. W., active 1776-1784., 1 (Box 143)
      - Individual Artists., 61 (Box 143)
        - Kaschauer, Jacob, active 1429- died before 1463., 5 (Box 143)
        - Klinger, Max, 1857-1920., 5 (Box 143)
        - Koenig, Fritz, 1924-., 11 (Box 143)
        - Kolbe, Georg, 1877-1947., 17 (Box 143)
        - Kollwitz, Kathe, 1867-1945., 5 (Box 143)
        - Krafft, Adam, 1450-1507., 15 (Box 143)
        - Krumper, Hans, c.1570-1634., 4 (Box 143)
    - L, 85 (Box 144)
      - Miscellaneous Artists., 7 (Box 144)
        - Lackner, Andreas, XVI C., 2 (Box 144)
        - Leinberger, Simon, circle of, c.1460., 2 (Box 144)
        - Leyden, Nikolaus Gerhardt von, XV c., 2 (Box 144)
        - Luidl, Lorenz, 1668-1719., 1 (Box 144)
        - Lupertz, Marcus, 1941-., 1 (Box 144)
      - Individual Artists., 78 (Box 144)
        - Lederer, Hugo, 1871-1940., 4 (Box 144)
        - Lederer, Jorg, c.1470-1550., 3 (Box 144)
        - Lehmbruck, Wilhelm, 1881-1919., 35 (Box 144)
        - Leinberger, Hans, active 1511-1530., 23 (Box 144)
        - Luchsperger, Lorenz, XVI c., 12 (Box 145)
    - M, 48 (Box 145)
      - Miscellaneous Artists., 11 (Box 145)
        - Mack, Heinz, 1931-., 3 (Box 145)
        - Matare, Ewald, 1887-1965., 2 (Box 145)
        - Meier-Denninghoff, Brigitte, XX C., 1 (Box 145)
        - Meissner, J. H., c.1700-1770., 1 (Box 145)
        - Messerschmidt, F., 1736-1777., 1 (Box 145)
        - Metzel, Olaf, 1952-., 1 (Box 145)
        - Metzner, Franz, 1870-1919., 1 (Box 145)
        - Mobius, XX C., 1 (Box 145)
      - Individual Artists., 37 (Box 145)
        - Marcks, Gerhard, 1889-1981., 8 (Box 145)
        - Meit, Conrad, active 1496-1550/1., 25 (Box 145)
        - Moll, B. F., 1717-1785., 2 (Box 145)
        - Multscher, Hans, c.1400-1467., 2 (Box 145)
    - N, O, 15 (Box 146)
      - Miscellaneous Artists., 2 (Box 146)
        - Nahl, Johann August, 1752-1825., 1 (Box 146)
        - Neudecker, Johann, XVIII C., 1 (Box 146)
      - Individual Artists., 13 (Box 146)
        - Notke, Bernt, 1440-1509., 11 (Box 146)
        - Ochsenhausen, School of Multschers, c.1400., 2 (Box 146)
    - P, Q, 33 (Box 146)
      - Miscellaneous Artists., 2 (Box 146)
        - Pagels, Joachim Herm, ?., 1 (Box 146)
        - Parler, Heinrich, ?., 1 (Box 146)
      - Individual Artists., 31 (Box 146)
        - Pacher, Michael, XV C., 18 (Box 146)
        - Permoser, Balthasar, 1651-1732., 5 (Box 146)
        - Petel, Georg, 1601-1634., 7 (Box 146)
          Also known as Jorg Petle.
        - Piene, Otto, 1928-., 1 (Box 146)
    - R, 96 (Box 147)
      - Miscellaneous Artists., 7 (Box 147)
        - Raentz, Johann David and L. W. the Younger, XVII C?., 1 (Box 147)
        - Riese, Carl F., XIX C., 1 (Box 147)
        - Rietschel, Ernst F., 1804-1861., 2 (Box 147)
        - Ringwald, Klaus, XX C., 2 (Box 147)
        - Rudolph, Jacob, XX C., 1 (Box 147)
      - Individual Artists., 89 (Box 147)
        - Rauch, Daniel C., 1777-1857., 3 (Box 147)
        - Riemenschneider, Tilman, 1460-1531., 86 (Box 147)
          - Miscellaneous locations., 36 (Box 147)
          - Bamberg., 4 (Box 147)
          - Munich., 9 (Box 147)
          - Rothenburg., 7 (Box 147)
          - Wurzburg., 30 (Box 148)
    - S, 141 (Box 148)
      - Miscellaneous Artists., 20 (Box 148)
        - Schardt, Johann Gregor von der, 1530-c.1580., 1 (Box 148)
        - Scheibe, Richard, XX C., 1 (Box 148)
        - Schlemmer, Oskar, 1888-1943., 2 (Box 148)
        - Schoemaker, XIX-XX C., 1 (Box 148)
        - Schotz, Benno, XX C., 1 (Box 148)
        - Schramm, Friedrich, active 1480., 1 (Box 148)
        - Schreiter, Gerhard, XX C., 1 (Box 148)
        - Schrieber, Ludwig Garbriel, 1907-., 1 (Box 148)
        - Schutlze, Bernard, 1915-., 2 (Box 148)
        - Schweigardt, Frederic, XX C., 1 (Box 148)
        - Schwitters, Kurt, 1887-1948., 1 (Box 148)
        - Simering, L. R., 1835-1905., 1 (Box 148)
        - Slodtz, Sebastian, 1655-1726., 1 (Box 148)
        - Steger, Milly, 1881-1948., 1 (Box 148)
        - Steinhart, Matthias, XVII C., 1 (Box 148)
        - Stuhlhoff, Sebastian, XVIII C., 1 (Box 148)
        - Szymanski, Rolf, 1923-., 2 (Box 148)
      - Individual Artists., 121 (Box 148)
        - Schadow, J. G., 1764-1850., 9 (Box 148)
        - Schluter, Andreas, 1662-1714., 4 (Box 148)
        - Schmaedl, F. X. 1705-1777., 2 (Box 148)
        - Schwanthaler, Ludwig von, 1802-1848., 3 (Box 148)
        - Sintenis, Renee, 1888-1965., 5 (Box 148)
        - Stoss, Veit, 1447-1542., 83 (Box 149)
          - Miscellaneous locations., 12 (Box 149)
          - Krakow., 50 (Box 149)
          - Nurnberg., 21 (Box 149)
        - Straub, Johann Baptist, 1704-1784., 5 (Box 150)
        - Sturm, Anton, 1690-1757., 6 (Box 150)
        - Syrlin, Jorg the Elder, active 1430-1491, and the Younger, active 1475-1521., 4 (Box 150)
    - T, 8 (Box 150)
      - Miscellaneous Artists., 1 (Box 150)
        - Trockel, Rosemarie, 1952-., 1 (Box 150)
      - Individual Artists., 7 (Box 150)
        - Taschner, Ignatius, 1871-1913., 5 (Box 150)
        - Tuaillon, Louis, 1862-1917., 2 (Box 150)
    - U, V, 18 (Box 150)
      - Miscellaneous Artists., 5 (Box 150)
        - Uecker, Gunther, 1930-., 4 (Box 150)
        - Uhlmann, Hans, 1900-., 1 (Box 150)
      - Individual Artists., 13 (Box 150)
        - Vischer, Peter the Elder, 1460-1529., 7 (Box 150)
        - Vischer, Peter the Younger, 1487-1528., 6 (Box 150)
    - W, 22 (Box 150)
      - Miscellaneous Artists., 7 (Box 150)
        - Warneke, Heinz, 1895-1983., 1 (Box 150)
        - Weidtz, Cristoph, ?., 1 (Box 150)
        - Weit, Conrad, ?., 1 (Box 150)
        - Winzer, Franz, XIX C., 1 (Box 150)
        - Wolf, Friedrich, 1833-1884., 1 (Box 150)
        - Wolff, Albert, 1816-1892., 1 (Box 150)
        - Worms, Eckhard von, active 1279., 1 (Box 150)
      - Individual Artists., 15 (Box 150)
        - Wagner, Johann Peter Alexander, 1730-1809., 2 (Box 150)
        - Wenzinger, Christian, 1710-1797., 2 (Box 150)
        - Witten, Hans, active 1500-1525., 6 (Box 150)
        - Wrba, Georg, 1872-1939., 5 (Box 150)
    - X, Y, Z, 8 (Box 150)
      - Miscellaneous Artists., 8 (Box 150)
        - Zeckl, Johann, 1691/4-1728., 1 (Box 150)
        - Zeiller, Johann Jakob, 1710-1783., 2 (Box 150)
        - Zurn, Jorg the Elder, 1583-1635., 1 (Box 150)
        - Zurn, Martin, 1590-1665., 2 (Box 150)
        - Zurn, Michael the Elder, active 1624-1665., 1 (Box 150)
        - Zurn, Michael the Younger, 1626-1691., 1 (Box 150)
- Holland (Box 151)
  - Anonymous Artists., 41 (Box 151)
    - Miscellaneous works., 4 (Box 151)
    - XV Century., 28 (Box 151)
    - XVI Century., 9 (Box 151)
  - Artists, Known., 51 (Box 151)
    - Miscellaneous Artists, A-Z., 21 (Box 151)
      - Beyerman, Louise, XX C., 2 (Box 151)
      - Doesburg, Theo van, 1883-1931., 1 (Box 151)
      - Dries, Joan, XX C., 1 (Box 151)
      - Engels, Pieter, 1938-., 1 (Box 151)
      - Esser, Vincent Pieter Semeijn, 1914-., 1 (Box 151)
      - Grupello, Gabriel de, 1644-1713., 1 (Box 151)
      - Keyser, Hendrick de, 1565-1621., 1 (Box 151)
      - Kneulman, Carel, 1915-., 1 (Box 151)
      - Krop, Hildo, XX C., 1 (Box 151)
      - Master of the S. George Altar in Kalkar, active c.1490., 1 (Box 151)
      - Master of the Utrecht S. Martin and the Four Saints, active c.1455-1465., 1 (Box 151)
      - Mattos, Henri Teixeira de, 1856-1908., 2 (Box 151)
      - Pallandt, Charlotte van, 1898-1959., 1 (Box 151)
      - Schoonhoven, Jan, 1914-., 2 (Box 151)
      - Verhulst, Rombout, 1624-1698., 3 (Box 151)
        Some works done with W. de Keyser, 1603-1674.
      - Wenckebach, Ludwig Oswald, 1895-., 1 (Box 151)
    - Individual Artists, A-Z., 30 (Box 152)
      - Appel, Karel, 1921-., 3 (Box 152)
      - Master A B, XVII C., 3 (Box 152)
      - Vantongerloo, Georges, 1886-1965., 4 (Box 152)
      - Vries, Adriaen de, 1560-1643., 11 (Box 152)
      - Wesel, Adriaen van, c.1420-1499., 9 (Box 152)
- Hungary (Box 152)
  - Miscellaneous Artists., 6 (Box 152)
    - Meister Paul von Leutschau, XIII C., 1 (Box 152)
    - Moholy-Nagy, Laszlo, 1895-1946., 5 (Box 152)
- Iceland (Box 152)
  - Miscellaneous Artists., 4 (Box 152)
    - Jonsson, Einar, XIX-XX C., 2 (Box 152)
    - Narfasson, Benedikt, XVI C., 2 (Box 152)
- Israel (Box 152)
  - Miscellaneous Artists., 11 (Box 152)
    - Agam, Yaacov, 1928-., 11 (Box 152)